<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Yellow Envelope</title>
    <description>Letters to myself.</description>
    <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bhyrava.me/write/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>IE Poetry at IIIT-Hyderabad.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The IIIT-Hyderabad library is as old as the college itself. We’re doing a column on it at Ping this issue&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so I won’t elaborate, but the fact that it has been well-organized and maintained for over 18 years now is very impressive, and the efficiency is reflected in its collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be no reason for the library of a college as technical and computer-science oriented as ours to have a good poetry collection, and that it why I was surprised to see the likes of Dylan Thomas, William Wordsworth, T.S.Eliot, Thomas Hardy and William Blake stacked up against each other in the lonely racks of the poetry section, back in first year. How many students before me had picked up those titles and flipped through the pages? How many had spent a rainy evening reading Shakespearean sonnets? I wish I knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one limited way to find out, and that was to look at the cards at the back of the books, and see who had issued the books before. There were a few names scribbled here and there, but they were far and few in between, and dated back to 2009 or earlier. One day, when I’m really bored, I’d like to go make a list, just for the heck of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was interested in, today, however, was poetry in Indian English. How many modern poets who wrote in IE did the library boast of? After lunch, I spent about two hours sifting through the racks, head tilted sideways to read the slanting titles, because there were too many books to be taken down in stacks and glanced through while sitting down on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/moraes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moraes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised, again, to see a good collection, and made a list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr.Rukmini Bhaya Nair&lt;/em&gt;, the eminent linguist and poet who is currently a professor at IIT-Delhi&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sri Sitakant Mahapatra&lt;/em&gt;, an IAS officer and poet, who was awarded the Padma Vibhushan and Sahitya Akademi awards for his literature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manohar Shetty&lt;/em&gt;, the Goan poet, who has been a Homi Bhaba Fellow and a Sahitya Akademi Fellow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leela Gandhi&lt;/em&gt;, professor of English at Brown University (and the great-granddaughter of Mahatma Gandhi)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vikram Seth&lt;/em&gt;, arguably India’s most popular writer and poet, today.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The late &lt;em&gt;Dom Moraes&lt;/em&gt;, who proably holds the unanimous honour of being the greatest Indian poet of his era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad, is it? Apart from these poets, there were other collections of Indian Poetry in English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Both Sides of The Sky (Post -Independence Indian Poetry in English)”, &lt;em&gt;Eunice de Souza&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Early Indian Poetry in English: An Anthology 1829-1947”, &lt;em&gt;Eunice de Souza&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Illustrated History of Indian Literature in English”, &lt;em&gt;Arvind Krisha Mehrotra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Indian English Women Poets”, &lt;em&gt;Ansur Rahman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this collection is quite limited, and leaves something lacking for the poetry enthusiasts. So I decided to make a list of poetry books I would personally like to see in college, and forwarded it to the Library Committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-list&quot;&gt;The List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Lie of Dawns: Collected Poems of &lt;em&gt;Jayanta Mahapatra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;310/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Veiled Suite : The Collected Poems - &lt;em&gt;Agha Shahid Ali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;265/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A Necklace of Skulls - &lt;em&gt;Eunice de Souza&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Living Rooms - &lt;em&gt;Manohar Shetty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;130/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Slow Startle - &lt;em&gt;Rohan Chhetri&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;350/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Painting that Red Circle White - &lt;em&gt;Mihir Vatsa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;First Infinities - &lt;em&gt;Vijay Nambisan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;250/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Safe House - &lt;em&gt;Menka Shivdasini&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Life and Times of Mr S: Poems - &lt;em&gt;Vivek Narayanan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;230/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Countries Of The Body - &lt;em&gt;Tishani Doshi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;150/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Erotext: Desire, Disease, Delusion, Dream, Downpour - &lt;em&gt;Sudeep Sen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;260/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lullaby of The Ever Returning - &lt;em&gt;Sarbjeet Garcha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Seduction of Delhi - &lt;em&gt;Abhay K&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;190/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Broomrider’s Book of the Dead - &lt;em&gt;Mukta Sambrani&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;400/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vanishing Acts: New and Selected Poems, 1985-2005 by &lt;em&gt;Ranjit Hoskote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;175/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;When God is a Traveller by &lt;em&gt;Arundhathi Subramaniam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;250/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Portraits of the Space We Occupy - &lt;em&gt;C.P. Surendran&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;200/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100 Poems 1985-2005 - &lt;em&gt;Mani Rao&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;730/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Missing Rib: Collected Poems 1973-2015 - &lt;em&gt;K.Satchidanandan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;750/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I Dreamt a Horse Fell from the Sky - &lt;em&gt;Adil Jussawalla&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;400/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Collected Poems of &lt;em&gt;Vikram Seth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;320/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Collected Poems of &lt;em&gt;Jeet Thayil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;400/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Collected Poems 1969-2014 - &lt;em&gt;Arvind Krishna Mehrotra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;350/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Collected Poems of &lt;em&gt;A.K.Ramanujan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dancing Earth by &lt;em&gt;Robin Singh Ngangom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;310/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Oxford Anthology of Modern Indian Poetry - &lt;em&gt;Dharwadker Vinay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;320/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Oxford India Anthology of 12 Modern Indian Poets -  &lt;em&gt;Mehrotra Arvind Krishna&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;270/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;60 Indian Poets - &lt;em&gt;Jeet Thayil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;410/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Bloodaxe Book of Contemporary Indian Poets - &lt;em&gt;Jeet Thayil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,100/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;40 under 40 - &lt;em&gt;Nabina Das, Semeen Ali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;400/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9950/-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correspondence went as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/mail1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mail_1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/mail2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mail_2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/mail3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mail_3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I need to compile a list of journals, and send a separate list for that, and hope for a favourable reply. I’ll post an update as soon as I get one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The first issue will be out in a week or two, hopefully, and I’ll definitely blog about that. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Apart from being renowned for her academic work and poetry, she is also known as a critic of the Hindutva ideology. More on her &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rukmini_Bhaya_Nair&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Eunice de Souza is a poet herself, read about her &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eunice_de_Souza&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/iiit-h/2016/09/22/paih/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/iiit-h/2016/09/22/paih/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Till The Volta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I clicked on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.srinivasrayaprol.in/srinivas-rayaprol-poetry-prize-2016-call-for-entries/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link on the 1st of September, I had no idea that it would lead me down a path which would bring about such a radical change in the way I looked at poetry, within three weeks. I’m struggling to come to terms with new discoveries, and need to put them all down in words and calm down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided that I’ll break up my narrative into two parts - my journey down the poet’s road till the 1st of September 2016, and the events that followed after that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post covers the first part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d started loving poetry when I was a kid because of the linguistic beauty of words, because of the way alliteration, rhyme and metre&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; were pleasing to the ear. Even when we’d moved on from rhymed couplets and quartrains to free verse at St.Xavier’s School in Durgapur, we were taught to ‘appreciate’ the metaphors and similies, to note the clever use of puns and punctuations which broke the flow of narrative. Non-linearity, personification, choice of words - these were the things I noticed, and enjoyed. Henry Chappels, my school teacher in seventh grade, encouraged my enthusiasm, and this is when I wrote my earliest poetry&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.It was very childish - I’d started, as I guess most do, by imitating form and rhyme from poems I’d already read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin:60px&quot;&gt;
Give to me the life I love,&lt;br /&gt;
Let the lave go by me,&lt;br /&gt;
Give the jolly heaven above&lt;br /&gt;
And the byway nigh me.&lt;br /&gt;
Bed in the bush with stars to see,&lt;br /&gt;
Bread I dip in the river&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s the life for a man like me;&lt;br /&gt;
There&#39;s the life for ever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Vagabond&lt;/i&gt;, R.L.Stevenson&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only when the semantics and pragmatics got involved that the trouble started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between 2010-2011, when I started thinking about the meaning of poetry, things changed. Reading poetry was a different experience, and writing it was now a nightmare. Poems now had to &lt;em&gt;mean&lt;/em&gt; something, and this &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; needed to be grave and serious, in my head. My poems were no longer satisfactory, I needed to do better. At 16, full of fantastic dreams, I somehow decided that I needed to understand poetry&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The person encouraging me now, when I was in high school, was again an English teacher. Her name is Aparna Venson, and she spent too many hours reading my poems and telling me they were good even when both of us knew they weren’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, for more than four years now, I have struggled with this idea of reading and writing poetry, and have felt miserably isolated within the margins of a page I don’t understand. I couldn’t talk to the poets whose works I read - they were all long gone, buried in graves in faraway countries. I used to sing &lt;em&gt;Charge of the Light Brigade&lt;/em&gt; to myself, cycling from a Math tuition to a Hindi one. &lt;em&gt;The Inchcape Rock&lt;/em&gt; was memorized and mumbled in sleep. &lt;em&gt;The Road Not Taken&lt;/em&gt; was read and reread a hundred times from my school textbook. But how does one reach out to Tennyson or Southey or Frost?  And the ones whom I knew from India - they were generations and social constructs apart from me - the inaccessible Vikram Seths of the country. I had no idea who was writing poetry in English in 2012, no idea whom I could talk to about what I was writing. How do you initiate conversation about polyandry over an orhtodox dinner table, when you’re 17 years old? How do you talk about a drunk Welsh poet&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with teachers who want you to understand sp&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; hybridisation? How do you tell your ‘cool’ friends about your softie obsession with iambic pentameter when they’re arguing about which football club has the better center forward?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I wrote letters. To Vikram Seth, to Ruskin Bond, to Jug Suraiya&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to addresses I’d pick off the back of the only literary magazine I knew, &lt;em&gt;Indian Literature&lt;/em&gt;. These letters were letters asking doubts. Begging for guidance, initiating conversation of sorts. For over six months, I received no reply. I didn’t mind, at first, it was fun sealing up yellow envelopes. sticking stamps on them, and sneaking them off to the Vidyanagar PO. I was probably one of the very few 17 year old kids who could navigate their way through a post office queue, and it was a quietly romantic experience. But it was discouraging to receive no reply, for I had a lot of questions about poetry, and they bothered me when left unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first reply did arrive, though, and it on the 25th of May, 2012, from Prof. Jayanta Mahapatra&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, a poet almost five times my age. Along with a letter, he sent me the last printed copy of &lt;em&gt;Chandrabhaga&lt;/em&gt;, the literary journal he once edited.  His letter was warm and concise, and I remember reading the square piece of paper while sitting at the foot of my bed. If you’re ever received a personal letter, written in the thin composed hand of a person you’ve never met or seen before, you would know that such moments are hard to forget. It was a significant turn of events for me, perhaps one without which I would have probably given up on poetry. Jayanta ‘Sir’ would go on to humour me with more replies over the next year, before our correspondence stopped. He would try to tell me how poetry was born out of pain for him, and I would pretend to understand. (“Yes, of course we were pretentious – what else is youth for?”). I remember nights when I would pore over the same page of &lt;em&gt;Chandrabhaga&lt;/em&gt;, trying to understand what the words in the poems were doing, and what they were trying to convey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin:60px&quot;&gt;
His tongue drags to and fro&lt;br /&gt;
inside its crusted bell&lt;br /&gt;
to hit the right note.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;This Won&#39;t Hurt&lt;/i&gt;, Adil Jussawalla&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were my first forays into modern Indian poetry in English - the poems which talked about things that were directly around me - both tangible and intangible. You can relate more to poetry which is born of similar constructs in society (just the way you can relate more to poetry written in your mother-tongue, but that’s another story&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). And reading these poems in &lt;em&gt;Chandrabhaga&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Indian Literature&lt;/em&gt;, I had an endless array of questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also around this time that decided to go knock on Prof. Shiv K. Kumar’s door. I’d come to know of him because of his poem &lt;em&gt;Mother’s Day&lt;/em&gt; in our English textbook, and I found out that he lived just behind my brother’s old school. So on the afternoon of the 21st of January, 2013, armed with a couple of his books ( &lt;em&gt;Losing My Way&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Woolgathering&lt;/em&gt; ) and no money in my pockets - I ended up at Prof. Shiv K. Kumar’s doorstep&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lady who opened the door eyed me from head to toe, suspiciously keeping her distance.&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Good afternoon, ma’am. Is this Prof. Shiv K. Kumar’s house?”&lt;br /&gt;
A moment of silence, as she scrutinised my unkempt appearance once more.&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes, who are you?”&lt;br /&gt;
“My name is Sriharsh, I wrote to Prof. Kumar, twice. I want to be a poet.”&lt;br /&gt;
She chuckled at this. “You want to be a poet?” she said, amused.&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes, ma’am. A poet.”&lt;br /&gt;
More chuckling. “How old are you, again?”&lt;br /&gt;
“I’m 18, ma’am.”&lt;br /&gt;
Silence.&lt;br /&gt;
“You could be a ruffian. I don’t think I should let you in.”&lt;br /&gt;
I’d walked quite a lot and was tired and thirsty, and was in such dire straits financially&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that I couldn’t afford to make this trip all the way across the city, again. “I’m a student, ma’am, studying for IIT-JEE. I’m not a ruffian, please believe me. I’ve walked a long way, and am tired and thirsty.”&lt;br /&gt;
“How do I know you’re not a &lt;em&gt;goonda&lt;/em&gt;? You look like one. How do I know you won’t come in, beat up and rob us old people, and make away with all the valuables?”&lt;br /&gt;
I pulled out the two books on poetry I had, and showed them to her. Then I handed out my identity card, too, to her. She looked at them all, and then handed them back.&lt;br /&gt;
“Come in, quickly, but don’t make too much noise. He doesn’t like to be disturbed, it’s nap time as it is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin:60px&quot;&gt;
We do it differently&lt;br /&gt;
in this dark continent.&lt;br /&gt;
Not just once a year&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
a string of spurious verses&lt;br /&gt;
ensconced in a bouquet&lt;br /&gt;
shaped like Chinese house of dreams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mother&#39;s Day&lt;/i&gt;, Shiv K. Kumar&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prof. Kumar, 91 at that time, waved the letters I’d written to him at me, angrily. “Who writes such long letters, eh? And in such small handwriting? Do you know how difficult it is to read your words?”&lt;br /&gt;
I didn’t reply. I didn’t think I was supposed to. I stared at my feet guiltily instead, like I was a schoolkid caught red-handed in some inexcusable crime, and had now been dragged in front of the headmaster. &lt;br /&gt;
Prof. Kumar leaned back in his chair, annoyed. “Wants to be a poet, huh.” He muttered to himself.&lt;br /&gt;
“I’m sorry, sir. I didn’t think of it.”&lt;br /&gt;
“You should, if you want to be a poet. Why do you want to, anyway? Do you know what it means to be a poet?”&lt;br /&gt;
I mumbled something about words and how I liked them. He cut me in between.&lt;br /&gt;
“You don’t, see. Look around you - what do you see?”&lt;br /&gt;
There were steel racks all across the walls, filled with books. I was surrounded by a sea of hardbounds, paperbacks and newsletters. &lt;br /&gt;
“A lot of books, sir.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes, a lot of books, and I’ve read all of them. I needed to. Poetry is about people, about the world around you. You need to read a lot of poetry and be able to feel emotions before you want to convey them.” He looked at me, as if trying to gauge if I was following. “Give me the poems you’ve written.”&lt;br /&gt;
I pulled out my sheets, and handed them over. Two of those poems would go on to be published in &lt;em&gt;Indian Literature&lt;/em&gt;, but I didn’t know of it, back then. Prof. Kumar adjusted his glasses, and started reading.
“Very raw. And lacks emotion,” he said, five minutes later, handing me back the sheets. “You need to practise writing poetry, your technique is very weak, and your words don’t really move me.”&lt;br /&gt;
I nodded.&lt;br /&gt;
“But you do have the ability. Keep at it. Try to understand how you feel, and find ways to express it. Practise.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Thank you, sir.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Have you actually read my poems?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Sir, I - “&lt;br /&gt;
“You should read &lt;em&gt;Which of my selves do you wish to speak to?&lt;/em&gt; Do you have a copy?”&lt;br /&gt;
“No, Sir, I don’t.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Then take mine. But I won’t give it for free, it’s the only copy I have left. Can you pay for it?”&lt;br /&gt;
I couldn’t. I needed that money to get home.&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes, sir, I can.”&lt;br /&gt;
The transaction was made, and Prof. Kumar gave me the contact details of another person he asked me to talk to.&lt;br /&gt;
“His name is Gopal, he’ll help you with poetry. Contact him.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Thank you, sir.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Don’t come to my house, again. I don’t have the time.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes, sir.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remember the way he shuffled away to his bedroom while I left. &lt;em&gt;Wants to be a poet, huh&lt;/em&gt;, he was muttering to himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contacted Mr.Gopal, but he wasn’t very interested, and after a couple of visits to his home in Secunderabad, I gave up. JEE exams were looming, and I had already messed up my preparations. Prof. Jayanta Mahapatra hadn’t replied in a while, either, and it was a long time before I would read or write poetry or try to reach out to other poets again. I spent the next year working on an unfinished fantasy fiction novel, and then got into IIIT-Hyderabad in 2014, after which college life swept me away into a different person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did write the occasional poem, and my old ones got published in &lt;em&gt;Indian Literature&lt;/em&gt; twice, in &lt;em&gt;Muse Online&lt;/em&gt; once, and in my college magazine. But I had stopped writing and reading poetry, and stopped calling myself a poet. There were times when I tried over the last year, but I never seemed to have the right mindset and silence for it, and couldn’t come up with anything. This distance remained for two more years, and it ate away at me, as if I had lost an identity. I had lost touch with poetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until three weeks ago, until the volta.&lt;br /&gt;
But that is a story for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I hope to cover a basic introduction to metre, soon, in a future blog post. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;More on Henry Sir and the poems I wrote back then, in another post. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This ‘understanding’, to me, meant finding answers to some crucial questions, details of which I’ll delve into later. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Dylan Thomas was a huge influence, I imitated the villanelle back then, and still imitate his letters. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Jug Suraiya actually replied. I had written to him in response to a TOI editorial piece he’d based on writing letters, and his reply - a scrawny bunch of lines on ruled paper - is something I’ve stashed away. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Prof. Jayanta Mahapatra’s poetry can unnerve the casual reader. Not only was he prolific in his own writings, he spent a lot of time translating Oriya poetry into English, effectively defining an era of Indian poetry in English. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There is another blog post in here, somewhere - I could on and on about the frustration one feels when he cannot express himself in the tongue that feels most comfortable to him. Colonialism, what have you done? &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A comedy of errors preceded this, however, where I ended up in the wrong Kakatiya Nagar of the city - there were apparently four of them. The auto driver who told me this in Tollychowki was laughing his head off at me and the printouts of the Google Maps I had in my hands ( I had no internet-enable phone back then). Good old times. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I hadn’t told my parents anything about this journey - or the books I bought, or the typewriter I’d purchased, or the money I spent on stationery for letters, or the money I’d spent on MMTS rides. I was truly broke. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/2016/09/19/deluge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/2016/09/19/deluge/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dahl&#39;s &#39;Boy&#39; - A Note</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do not read this book if you haven’t read any of Dahl’s works already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, don’t. You will not be able to appreicate his style, you will not be able to chuckle at a passage which strongly reminds you of his other tales, quite a few reference will go whizzing over your head and, most importantly, you will not be so attached to his memories as someone who’s read his other works is. The book is a lot more fun - let me emphasise &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; for you - when you’re a Dahl regular. Go read some children’s books first - try &lt;em&gt;The Twits, Matilda, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory, The Witches&lt;/em&gt;; then move on to his adult works - go for &lt;em&gt;Kiss, Kiss, Switch Bitch&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Someone Like You&lt;/em&gt;. Then come back to this little masterpiece, and savour it like a delicious new flavour of candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esio Trot, stel evom no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/books/2016/07/23/b1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/books/2016/07/23/b1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poem I - James Fenton</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin:60px&quot;&gt;
What would the dead want from us &lt;br /&gt;
Watching from their cave?&lt;br /&gt;
Would they have us forever howling?&lt;br /&gt;
Would they have us rave&lt;br /&gt;
Or disfigure ourselves, or be strangled&lt;br /&gt;
Like some ancient emperor&#39;s slave? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
None of my dead friends were emperors&lt;br /&gt;
With such exorbitant tastes&lt;br /&gt;
And none of them were so vengeful&lt;br /&gt;
As to have all their friends waste&lt;br /&gt;
Waste quiet away in sorrow&lt;br /&gt;
Disfigured and defaced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I think the dead would want us&lt;br /&gt;
To weep for what they have lost.&lt;br /&gt;
I think that our luck in continuing&lt;br /&gt;
Is what would affect them most.&lt;br /&gt;
But time would find them generous&lt;br /&gt;
And less self-engrossed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And time would find them generous&lt;br /&gt;
As they used to be&lt;br /&gt;
And what else would they want from us&lt;br /&gt;
But an honoured place in our memory,&lt;br /&gt;
A favourite room, a hallowed chair,&lt;br /&gt;
Privilege and celebrity?&lt;br /&gt;
And so the dead might cease to grieve&lt;br /&gt;
And we might make amends&lt;br /&gt;
And there might be a pact between&lt;br /&gt;
Dead friends and living friends.&lt;br /&gt;
What our dead friends would want from us&lt;br /&gt;
Would be such living friends. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;James Fenton&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Bunch Of Letters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I write letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, hand-written letters, three-folded and put into yellow envelopes to be given to people. I do that because spoken words are hurried and perishable and are lost in the wind, while written words can be treasured and carry a quaint silence of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes, I write letters to myself. And since I spend more time at the keyboard and the screen than with a pen and a book these days, I would like to keep these letters stashed away in A Yellow Envelope - a space for my words, which is, funnily,  neither yellow nor an envelope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &quot;Writing is easy. All you have to do is cross out the wrong words.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Mark Twain&quot;&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sithoffside II | Welcome Home, Master Wayne</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kTh9VwK8QLg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/kTh9VwK8QLg/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sit Down Mourinho&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sit down Mourinho, Sit down Mourinho,” chanted the Old Trafford faithful as Manchester United and Chelsea settled for a disappointing goal-less draw in David Moyes’ first fixture at home. After all the hype that surrounded the meeting, the contest fizzled down to a cautious and non-clinical defensive display, with the most exciting moment being Mourinho frantically searching for his pen on the sidelines. Both the managers might believe that they’ve avoided an early hiccup, but Arsenal, Tottenham, Liverpool and City fans had the last laugh - instead of one rival dropping three points, both dropped two each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/roo13.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rooney&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mourinho started with a 4-6-0 formation. Quite obviously, he does not have too much faith in Demba Ba, Lukaku or Torres. Bereft of a world class striker, and with an array of No. 10s all cluttered into midfield, it was a disappointing starting eleven. But not a totally unexpected one, for such a defensive, ‘park-the-bus’ approach is quite characteristic of The Special One.  Mourinho, in fact, seemed to be quite happy with Chelsea squeezing out a draw. On another note, Juan Mata, who’s not exactly the Special One’s favourite, didn’t feature in the match:  he won’t feature for Chelsea at all, if one were to believe the transfer rumours.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance-wise, for Chelsea, Oscar had a few shots on target; Lampard lost possession too easily in the first half; Schurrle didn’t impress up the field and Terry and Cahill kept van Persie quiet. The rest of the match was woefully unimaginative. You’d expect more from an encounter with the Blues, especially after their 1-0 victory over United in their last meeting at Old Trafford. Perhaps Mourinho is more focused on winning Chelsea’s midweek match against Bayern Munich. That would explain why Ba, Torres, Lukaku and Mata weren’t given their share of playing time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, the Red Devils’ manager David Moyes might have a better reason to believe that he gained more than just one point from the draw, for the evening held a promise of things to come for Manchester United. The most notable and unexpected promise was that of Wayne Rooney, who put on a brilliant performance to remind the world of his worth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moyes started with a 4-2-3-1 formation - Van Persie leading the offense; Welbeck and Valencia on the wings; Cleverley and Carrick in central midfield; and the unchanged defense consisting of Evra, Vidic, Ferdinand and Jones.  But the highlight of the starting eleven was hopeful Kagawa unexpectedly losing out on the No.10 position to Wayne Rooney. Rooney - the man who, after Bale, has been the biggest topic of the transfer season’s rumours -  livened up proceedings throughout the match. He showed fierce intent, and kept at it throughout the whole match in an inspired display of energy, skill and sheer talent. He darted in and out of the midfield, had spirited runs further up the pitch, constantly threatened on the offense, notched up a string of beautiful passes to his credit, chased lost possession and won it back, and even had a few tries on goal - though all from outside the box.  If Welbeck had put in that cross in the penalty area - Rooney might have scored, too. He was a man possessed - and at the first opportunity he got, and he lost no time in proving why he is still the best striker in England. If he does stay (and in all probability he will) it bodes well for Moyes and his club.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving Rooney a starting place was an encouraging statement of intent from the manager; the positive reception meted out by the fans another plus point. The way they cheered the apparent ‘want-away’ striker was heartwarming, with even the Special One stating at the end of the match -“This must be a very special club, because in every other club in the world, when a player wants to leave they don’t support him.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had Terry and Cahill not put on a solid defensive display, and had Phil Jones, Welbeck and Valencia got their crosses into the danger area more often, it could have as well been a victory for Manchester United, and the perfect start to the season for David Moyes and Wayne Rooney. But the world of ‘if’s is infinite in football.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;United travel to Anfield for an away match on September 1st. Let’s wait see what that encounter has to offer. For the moment, though, I can almost hear Alfred Pennyworth speaking, and do excuse me when I join the Old Trafford faithful for another chant:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Welcome home, Master Wayne.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/09/07/so2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/09/07/so2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sithoffside I | An Early Showdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jose Mourinho’s Chelsea will be back at Old Trafford on Monday for another historic meeting with Manchester United.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
United fans - let’s face it. It won’t be a walk in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/mou13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mourinho&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moyes, back when he was with Everton, could never get the better of the Special One, with four losses and three draws to his credit. Yes - on Monday he’ll be having the premier league champions’ squad at his disposal, but it’s not too superior a squad to the one Mourinho currently commands. The Blues may be lacking the incisive striker as of now, but you cannot deny that they have the edge in the midfield. Solid Lampard, young Oscar, and the talented Hazard may prove to be more than a match for Tom Cleverley and Michael Carrick. All throughout the transfer window, the Red Devils’ fans anxiously awaited the new marquee midfield signing. There may be one soon, but there hasn’t been one, yet. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There were rumours, of course. More than a few names were linked with the club - Francesc Fabregas, Thiago Alcantara, Ilkay Gundogan, Yohan Cabaye, Luka Modric, Willian, Marouane Fellaini and even Bastian Schweinsteiger. And oh, the usual Cristiano-Ronaldo-returns-home gossip. Exciting rumours, but they remained just that – rumours. Manchester United have, so far, not succeeded in making any significant additions to the squad. Barcelona have rejected all the three bids United made for Francesc Fabregas, with the player himself stating in public that he was very happy at Camp Nou. There was a miserly bid made for the Everton duo of Marouane Fellaini and the talented Leighton Baines which, too, was rejected straightaway. Then came those ‘reports’ of players leaving. Mourinho was at it again - unsettling a ‘confused’ Rooney. Nani, some said, would be sold, now that Zaha had shown his potential; Valencia were linked with Chicarito. Again, there have been no major transfers away from the club, so far.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps David Moyes’ strategy is to wait till Real Madrid’s expected $140 million mega-signing Gareth Bale arrives at the Bernebau, and then grab Di Maria or Modric. Or perhaps, when the last Fabregas bid fails, we’ll sign Fellaini an hour before the window ends. Or perhaps there won’t be any marquee signing at all, and Cleverley and Zaha will score 30 goals each this season and Adnan Januzaj will turn out to be the new David Beckham. Unlikely, but hey -it’s football. You never know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway - what we do know is that we’ll have to depend on our offense again on Monday. Rooney remains an unlikely starter, irrespective of what Moyes might hint at in his press conferences. One year from now - Moyes might display his resolve by starting with Rooney on field, but this early in the season and his career - he’d want to play safe, and bank on certainty. In all probability, Van Persie and Welbeck will lead the attack, with Valencia, Cleverley, Carrick and Kagawa in the midfield. Giggs may get a look in, but he’ll probably be a sub, and if not, then he’ll certainly be subbed. Let us now pray that van Persie gets his usual quota, and hope that Welbeck’s fine form may seal off the contest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And who knows? This early showdown with the Special One may as well turn out be Moyes’ first stride out of Sir Alex’s colossal shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
