<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Yellow Envelope</title>
    <description>Letters to myself.</description>
    <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bhyrava.me/write/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The Facebook Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, I read an &lt;a href=&quot;https://backchannel.com/instagram-is-ruining-vacation-701086a67440?token=O0Y5FECEQlIMw53q#.4zwbne57l&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on Medium by &lt;a href=&quot;http://marypilon.com/&quot;&gt;Mary Pilon&lt;/a&gt;, author of a book called &lt;em&gt;The Monopolists&lt;/em&gt;. The article was called ‘Instagram Is Ruining Vacation’. Mary uses her Instragram snapshot of a temple in Cambodia (the one I’d seen in Tomb Raider ) to illustrate how people are more interested in capturing perfect pictures of their travels than in enjoying the travelling experience itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article echoed a belief I had been unknowingly harboured over the last year or so - the belief that social media was turning people into&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/06/01/fb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/06/01/fb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What would the dead want from us?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What would the dead want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching from their cave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would they have us forever howling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would they have us rave&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or disfigure ourselves, or be strangled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like some ancient emperor’s slave? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of my dead friends were emperors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such exorbitant tastes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And none of them were so vengeful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to have all their friends waste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waste quiet away in sorrow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disfigured and defaced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the dead would want us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To weep for what they have lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that our luck in continuing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is what would affect them most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But time would find them generous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And less self-engrossed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And time would find them generous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they used to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what else would they want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But an honoured place in our memory,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A favourite room, a hallowed chair,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privilege and celebrity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the dead might cease to grieve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we might make amends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there might be a pact between&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead friends and living friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What our dead friends would want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would be such living friends. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- James Fenton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Bunch Of Letters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I write letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, hand-written letters, three-folded and put into yellow envelopes to be given to people. I do that because spoken words are hurried and perishable and are lost in the wind, while written words can be treasured and carry a quaint silence of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes, I write letters to myself. And since I spend more time at the keyboard and the screen than with a pen and a book these days, I would like to keep these letters stashed away in A Yellow Envelope - a space for my words, which is, funnily,  neither yellow nor an envelope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &quot;Writing is easy. All you have to do is cross out the wrong words.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Mark Twain&quot;&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sithoffside I | An Early Showdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jose Mourinho’s Chelsea will be back at Old Trafford on Monday for another historic meeting with Manchester United.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
United fans - let’s face it. It won’t be a walk in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moyes, back when he was with Everton, could never get the better of the Special One, with four losses and three draws to his credit. Yes - on Monday he’ll be having the premier league champions’ squad at his disposal, but it’s not too superior a squad to the one Mourinho currently commands. The Blues may be lacking the incisive striker as of now, but you cannot deny that they have the edge in the midfield. Solid Lampard, young Oscar, and the talented Hazard may prove to be more than a match for Tom Cleverley and Michael Carrick. All throughout the transfer window, the Red Devils’ fans anxiously awaited the new marquee midfield signing. There may be one soon, but there hasn’t been one, yet. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There were rumours, of course. More than a few names were linked with the club - Francesc Fabregas, Thiago Alcantara, Ilkay Gundogan, Yohan Cabaye, Luka Modric, Willian, Marouane Fellaini and even Bastian Schweinsteiger. And oh, the usual Cristiano-Ronaldo-returns-home gossip. Exciting rumours, but they remained just that – rumours. Manchester United have, so far, not succeeded in making any significant additions to the squad. Barcelona have rejected all the three bids United made for Francesc Fabregas, with the player himself stating in public that he was very happy at Camp Nou. There was a miserly bid made for the Everton duo of Marouane Fellaini and the talented Leighton Baines which, too, was rejected straightaway. Then came those ‘reports’ of players leaving. Mourinho was at it again - unsettling a ‘confused’ Rooney. Nani, some said, would be sold, now that Zaha had shown his potential; Valencia were linked with Chicarito. Again, there have been no major transfers away from the club, so far.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps David Moyes’ strategy is to wait till Real Madrid’s expected $140 million mega-signing Gareth Bale arrives at the Bernebau, and then grab Di Maria or Modric. Or perhaps, when the last Fabregas bid fails, we’ll sign Fellaini an hour before the window ends. Or perhaps there won’t be any marquee signing at all, and Cleverley and Zaha will score 30 goals each this season and Adnan Januzaj will turn out to be the new David Beckham. Unlikely, but hey -it’s football. You never know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway - what we do know is that we’ll have to depend on our offense again on Monday. Rooney remains an unlikely starter, irrespective of what Moyes might hint at in his press conferences. One year from now - Moyes might display his resolve by starting with Rooney on field, but this early in the season and his career - he’d want to play safe, and bank on certainty. In all probability, Van Persie and Welbeck will lead the attack, with Valencia, Cleverley, Carrick and Kagawa in the midfield. Giggs may get a look in, but he’ll probably be a sub, and if not, then he’ll certainly be subbed. Let us now pray that van Persie gets his usual quota, and hope that Welbeck’s fine form may seal off the contest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And who knows? This early showdown with the Special One may as well turn out be Moyes’ first stride out of Sir Alex’s colossal shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
