<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Yellow Envelope</title>
    <description>Letters to myself.</description>
    <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://bhyrava.me/write/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The Facebook Dilemma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, I read an &lt;a href=&quot;https://backchannel.com/instagram-is-ruining-vacation-701086a67440?token=O0Y5FECEQlIMw53q#.4zwbne57l&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on Medium by &lt;a href=&quot;http://marypilon.com/&quot;&gt;Mary Pilon&lt;/a&gt;, author of a book called &lt;em&gt;The Monopolists&lt;/em&gt;. The article was called ‘Instagram Is Ruining Vacation’. Mary uses her Instragram snapshot of a temple in Cambodia (the one I’d seen in Tomb Raider ) to illustrate how people are more interested in capturing perfect pictures of their travels than in enjoying the travelling experience itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/angkorwat.png&quot; alt=&quot;Angkor Wat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article echoed a belief I had been unknowingly harboured over the last year or so - the belief that social media was turning people into&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/06/01/fb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/06/01/fb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What would the dead want from us?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What would the dead want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching from their cave?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would they have us forever howling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would they have us rave&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or disfigure ourselves, or be strangled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like some ancient emperor’s slave? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of my dead friends were emperors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such exorbitant tastes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And none of them were so vengeful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to have all their friends waste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waste quiet away in sorrow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disfigured and defaced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the dead would want us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To weep for what they have lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that our luck in continuing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is what would affect them most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But time would find them generous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And less self-engrossed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And time would find them generous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they used to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what else would they want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But an honoured place in our memory,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A favourite room, a hallowed chair,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privilege and celebrity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the dead might cease to grieve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we might make amends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there might be a pact between&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead friends and living friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What our dead friends would want from us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would be such living friends. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- James Fenton&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/poetry/archive/2016/05/14/P1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Bunch Of Letters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I write letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple, hand-written letters, three-folded and put into yellow envelopes to be given to people. I do that because spoken words are hurried and perishable and are lost in the wind, while written words can be treasured and carry a quaint silence of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes, I write letters to myself. And since I spend more time at the keyboard and the screen than with a pen and a book these days, I would like to keep these letters stashed away in A Yellow Envelope - a space for my words, which is, funnily,  neither yellow nor an envelope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &quot;Writing is easy. All you have to do is cross out the wrong words.&quot;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;footer&gt;&lt;cite title=&quot;Mark Twain&quot;&gt;Mark Twain&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 12:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/jekyll/pixyll/2016/05/05/new-letters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sithoffside II | Welcome Home, Master Wayne</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Sit down Mourinho, Sit down Mourinho,” chanted the Old Trafford faithful as Manchester United and Chelsea settled for a disappointing goal-less draw in David Moyes’ first fixture at home. After all the hype that surrounded the meeting, the contest fizzled down to a cautious and non-clinical defensive display, with the most exciting moment being Mourinho frantically searching for his pen on the sidelines. Both the managers might believe that they’ve avoided an early hiccup, but Arsenal, Tottenham, Liverpool and City fans had the last laugh - instead of one rival dropping three points, both dropped two each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kTh9VwK8QLg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/kTh9VwK8QLg/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sit Down Mourinho&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/roo13.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rooney&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mourinho started with a 4-6-0 formation. Quite obviously, he does not have too much faith in Demba Ba, Lukaku or Torres. Bereft of a world class striker, and with an array of No. 10s all cluttered into midfield, it was a disappointing starting eleven. But not a totally unexpected one, for such a defensive, ‘park-the-bus’ approach is quite characteristic of The Special One.  Mourinho, in fact, seemed to be quite happy with Chelsea squeezing out a draw. On another note, Juan Mata, who’s not exactly the Special One’s favourite, didn’t feature in the match:  he won’t feature for Chelsea at all, if one were to believe the transfer rumours.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance-wise, for Chelsea, Oscar had a few shots on target; Lampard lost possession too easily in the first half; Schurrle didn’t impress up the field and Terry and Cahill kept van Persie quiet. The rest of the match was woefully unimaginative. You’d expect more from an encounter with the Blues, especially after their 1-0 victory over United in their last meeting at Old Trafford. Perhaps Mourinho is more focused on winning Chelsea’s midweek match against Bayern Munich. That would explain why Ba, Torres, Lukaku and Mata weren’t given their share of playing time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, the Red Devils’ manager David Moyes might have a better reason to believe that he gained more than just one point from the draw, for the evening held a promise of things to come for Manchester United. The most notable and unexpected promise was that of Wayne Rooney, who put on a brilliant performance to remind the world of his worth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moyes started with a 4-2-3-1 formation - Van Persie leading the offense; Welbeck and Valencia on the wings; Cleverley and Carrick in central midfield; and the unchanged defense consisting of Evra, Vidic, Ferdinand and Jones.  But the highlight of the starting eleven was hopeful Kagawa unexpectedly losing out on the No.10 position to Wayne Rooney. Rooney - the man who, after Bale, has been the biggest topic of the transfer season’s rumours -  livened up proceedings throughout the match. He showed fierce intent, and kept at it throughout the whole match in an inspired display of energy, skill and sheer talent. He darted in and out of the midfield, had spirited runs further up the pitch, constantly threatened on the offense, notched up a string of beautiful passes to his credit, chased lost possession and won it back, and even had a few tries on goal - though all from outside the box.  If Welbeck had put in that cross in the penalty area - Rooney might have scored, too. He was a man possessed - and at the first opportunity he got, and he lost no time in proving why he is still the best striker in England. If he does stay (and in all probability he will) it bodes well for Moyes and his club.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving Rooney a starting place was an encouraging statement of intent from the manager; the positive reception meted out by the fans another plus point. The way they cheered the apparent ‘want-away’ striker was heartwarming, with even the Special One stating at the end of the match -“This must be a very special club, because in every other club in the world, when a player wants to leave they don’t support him.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had Terry and Cahill not put on a solid defensive display, and had Phil Jones, Welbeck and Valencia got their crosses into the danger area more often, it could have as well been a victory for Manchester United, and the perfect start to the season for David Moyes and Wayne Rooney. But the world of ‘if’s is infinite in football.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;United travel to Anfield for an away match on September 1st. Let’s wait see what that encounter has to offer. For the moment, though, I can almost hear Alfred Pennyworth speaking, and do excuse me when I join the Old Trafford faithful for another chant:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Welcome home, Master Wayne.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/09/07/so2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/09/07/so2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sithoffside I | An Early Showdown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jose Mourinho’s Chelsea will be back at Old Trafford on Monday for another historic meeting with Manchester United.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
United fans - let’s face it. It won’t be a walk in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/darthbhyrava/write/gh-pages/images/mou13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mourinho&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moyes, back when he was with Everton, could never get the better of the Special One, with four losses and three draws to his credit. Yes - on Monday he’ll be having the premier league champions’ squad at his disposal, but it’s not too superior a squad to the one Mourinho currently commands. The Blues may be lacking the incisive striker as of now, but you cannot deny that they have the edge in the midfield. Solid Lampard, young Oscar, and the talented Hazard may prove to be more than a match for Tom Cleverley and Michael Carrick. All throughout the transfer window, the Red Devils’ fans anxiously awaited the new marquee midfield signing. There may be one soon, but there hasn’t been one, yet. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There were rumours, of course. More than a few names were linked with the club - Francesc Fabregas, Thiago Alcantara, Ilkay Gundogan, Yohan Cabaye, Luka Modric, Willian, Marouane Fellaini and even Bastian Schweinsteiger. And oh, the usual Cristiano-Ronaldo-returns-home gossip. Exciting rumours, but they remained just that – rumours. Manchester United have, so far, not succeeded in making any significant additions to the squad. Barcelona have rejected all the three bids United made for Francesc Fabregas, with the player himself stating in public that he was very happy at Camp Nou. There was a miserly bid made for the Everton duo of Marouane Fellaini and the talented Leighton Baines which, too, was rejected straightaway. Then came those ‘reports’ of players leaving. Mourinho was at it again - unsettling a ‘confused’ Rooney. Nani, some said, would be sold, now that Zaha had shown his potential; Valencia were linked with Chicarito. Again, there have been no major transfers away from the club, so far.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps David Moyes’ strategy is to wait till Real Madrid’s expected $140 million mega-signing Gareth Bale arrives at the Bernebau, and then grab Di Maria or Modric. Or perhaps, when the last Fabregas bid fails, we’ll sign Fellaini an hour before the window ends. Or perhaps there won’t be any marquee signing at all, and Cleverley and Zaha will score 30 goals each this season and Adnan Januzaj will turn out to be the new David Beckham. Unlikely, but hey -it’s football. You never know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway - what we do know is that we’ll have to depend on our offense again on Monday. Rooney remains an unlikely starter, irrespective of what Moyes might hint at in his press conferences. One year from now - Moyes might display his resolve by starting with Rooney on field, but this early in the season and his career - he’d want to play safe, and bank on certainty. In all probability, Van Persie and Welbeck will lead the attack, with Valencia, Cleverley, Carrick and Kagawa in the midfield. Giggs may get a look in, but he’ll probably be a sub, and if not, then he’ll certainly be subbed. Let us now pray that van Persie gets his usual quota, and hope that Welbeck’s fine form may seal off the contest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And who knows? This early showdown with the Special One may as well turn out be Moyes’ first stride out of Sir Alex’s colossal shadow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://bhyrava.me/write/football/2013/08/23/so1/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
